cuteftp.com 2018-11-22

# Privacy Policy | Globalscape

Data privacy and data security are very important to Globalscape, Inc.  We are committed to respecting and protecting your privacy and to handling your personal data confidentially. In this Privacy Policy, we explain how we use any personal data we collect about you when you use our websites.   

Topics:  
•    What does “personal data” mean?  
•    Our data protection and data privacy principles  
•    What personal data do we collect?  
•    How do we collect and process personal data?  
•    Retention of personal data  
•    Sharing of personal data  
•    Cookies  
•    Third party advertising cookies  
•    Social plugins and social media widgets  
•    Google Analytics  
•    Protecting your personal data  
•    Access to your information and correction  
•    Other websites  
•    Children under the age of 13  
•    International users  
•    Mergers and acquisitions  
•    Changes to our privacy policy  
•    Contact us

**1\. What does “personal data” mean?**  
“Personal data” (sometimes referred to as “personal information” or “personally identifiable information”) means any information relating to an identified or identifiable natural person.  If we are not (or at least not without a disproportionate amount of time and effort) able to relate a direct link to you personally, this information is not personal data.  

**2\. Our data protection and data privacy principles**  
We have implemented measures designed to secure your personal data from accidental loss and from unauthorized access, use, alteration, and disclosure.  Our websites are principally designed in a way that limits the collection and processing of personal data to a minimum. Personal data we collect are stored on specially protected servers. Access is restricted to a limited number of authorized persons who need the access in order to administer our websites or ensure their proper functionality, especially with regard to technical support.

In certain cases, we are required to transfer personal data to third parties due to applicable legal requirements. This may be the case when there is reason to suspect a crime or misuse of our website.

**3\. What personal data do we collect?**  
The personal data we collect depends on your use of our website.  Depending upon your use, we may collect and process your name, address, telephone number, email address, the name of your employer, your phone number, and your IP address.  Website usage information is collected using cookies.

**4\. How do we collect and process personal data?**  
We take your privacy seriously and use your personal data to administer your account, deliver content, provide free trials, and inform you of product offerings.  More specific details of how our websites work and how we process personal data are provided below:

Marketing: We collect IP addresses of those who visit our website for marketing purposes.  We are not able to link IP addresses to a specific individual unless the individual has filled out a form on our site and provided additional personal data. From time to time, if you have consented and provided us your e-mail address, we will e-mail you our newsletters, free product updates, and other special offers. This subscription is voluntary and you are free to withdraw your consent at any time by clicking the unsubscribe link you will find in every email.  

Web services:  You will need to provide information to register for a “Globalscape Account.” The account allows you to access various Globalscape services online, such as managing your licenses or requesting support. Those services may be governed by a separate privacy statement which may differ from this policy.

Premium Content:  In order to access various content elements, such as Whitepapers or Videos, to reach dedicated marketing material, or to register for events, we will ask for your name, email address, and we may also request your address, the name of your employer, and your phone number. 

Free trials:  If you want to test our products, we will also ask for your name and email address, and we may also request your address, the name of your employer, and your phone number. This information will be used for sending out the activation code and to remind you of the end of the trial period. 

Contact Forms:  If you want to contact us by using our contact and support forms, you will be asked to provide your contact information (entry fields marked “*”), which we will exclusively process or use as necessary to get in contact with you and provide you with the information you desire. You are free to provide additional information (through the data fields not marked “*”), which we will process in line with all applicable data protection requirements. This data will be forwarded to the Globalscape or Globalscape Partner office in your country. The Globalscape or Globalscape Partner will use the data in order to get in contact with you.

User Surveys: Your participation in surveys is optional, although we may require your participation as a condition to a trial use of our software. We may ask you to describe the ways in which you and your company manage your IT resources or your experience with our software or Web sites. We may also ask you for demographic information such as age, gender, or areas of interest. We use this information to help us improve our software, plan marketing initiatives, and develop new products that may interest you. We may tie this information to other personal information that we have about you.

Purchase: In addition to obtaining your name and other personal information, we will identify and log your browser type when you purchase our software online. We use this information to help us detect piracy of our software.

Web Survey:  Your Web Survey results are collected and transmitted to you by our server.  The results and certain statistics regarding the results are stored on our server for the purpose of facilitating the reporting features of the software.  We do not view the results or statistics or share that information with any person.

Website Protection:  We may collect and retain IP addresses of those who visit our site in order to protect and defend our site against misuse.

**5\. Retention of personal data**  
The personal data we obtain for you will be retained up to indefinitely. 

**6\. Sharing of personal data**  
For the provision of certain services, we may make use of external service providers, such as Software as a Service (SaaS) providers. To the extent those external service providers need to have access to personal data, we ensure that any such access is limited to the extent necessary for the provision of the respective service. Furthermore, such external service providers of course have to submit themselves to comply with all applicable data protection regulations.

**7\. Cookies**  
A "cookie" is a small text file that is stored on computers, tablets, mobile phones and any device used to browse the Internet, capable of storing navigation information for statistical or functional purposes. Some cookies may be used to recognize the user viewing a particular website, make navigation easier, and customize the content. For example, cookies allow us to remember your actions and preferences so that you do not have to re-enter information each time you visit our site or navigate to another page.  Cookies also allow us to keep track of items you add to your shopping cart. There are several types of cookies, including, for example, browser cookies, session cookies, and persistent cookies.  When a browser is closed, session cookies are permanently lost.  Persistent cookies have a specified expiration date and will remain after a browser is closed.  For example, our shopping cart cookies are persistent cookies and will allow items to remain in your cart until a later visit to our site. 

While browsing on our websites, Globalscape may collect information about traffic flow and visits to the pages of our domain “Globalscape.com.” This information, obtained through cookies, will be treated in a secure manner.

We use different types of “cookies”:  
•    User identification and authentication  
 •   Shopping cart functionality  
•    User preference storage  
•    A/B performance testing  
•    Usage pattern assessment and traffic analysis  
•    Chat functionality  
•    Advertisement performance assessment and conversion tracking  
•    Remarketing/behavioral advertising

You can set your browser to accept or reject the setting of all or certain cookies, or to request to be notified when a cookie is set.  Each browser has specific configuration instructions. However, please be aware that the blocking of cookies may have the effect that you will not be able to use all of our website functions.

You can also set your cookies preferences in our Cookies Preference Center.

For further information about cookies, visit www.allaboutcookies.org.

**8\. Third party advertising cookies**  
Some advertisements on our website are served by third party advertisers.  The third parties may use cookies to collect information, including personal information, about your online activities over time and across different websites and other online services.  They may use this information to provide you with advertising based on your interests or other targeted content.

We do not control the third parties’ tracking technologies or how they may be used.  If you have any questions about an advertisement or other targeted content, you should contact the provider directly.  You can opt out of receiving targeted ads from members of the Network Advertising Initiative (“NAI”) on the NAI’s website: www.networkadvertising.org.

**9\. Social plugins and social media widgets**  
Our websites include different types of “social plugins” and social media widgets.    

These features may collect your IP address and information on which pages you are visiting on our websites, and they may set a cookie to enable the feature to function properly. Social media features and widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our website. Your interactions with these features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it.

If you do not want to be tracked by social media widgets, log out of all social networks you're logged in to before visiting our website.

**10\. Google analytics**  
We use Google Analytics to improve the user experience. Google Analytics helps us determine the number of visitors to our site and helps us understand how users find our site. Google Analytics may record your geographical location, device, internet browser, operating system, and IP address. We are not provided with information allowing us to link an individual to an IP address. If you do not want to be tracked by Google Analytics on our websites, you can download and install this browser add-on: https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout.

**11\. Access to your information and correction**  
At your request, we will inform you what personal data we have stored about you and for what purpose(s). Should we ever have stored incorrect data about you, despite our efforts to only store accurate and current data, we will correct it promptly upon recognition or at your request.  To request access to your personal data or a correction to personal data, please contact us at privacy@globalscape.com.

**12\. Other websites**  
This Privacy Policy only applies to Globalscape, Inc. websites and websites of our affiliates linking to this Privacy Policy.  Our websites contain multiple links to other websites.  Please be aware that we are not responsible for the privacy practices of those websites.  When visiting other websites, you should read those sites’ privacy policies.  

**13\. Children under the age of 13**  
Our websites are not intended for children.  No one under age 13 may provide any personal data on our websites.  We do not knowingly collect personal information from children under 13.  If you are under 13, do not use or provide any information on our websites.  If we learn we have collected or received personal information from a child under 13, we will delete that information.  If you believe we might have information from or about a child under 13, please contact us at privacy@globalscape.com.

**14\. Online Tracking**  
Globalscape does not respond to “do not track” (DNT) signals.

**15\. Your California Privacy Rights.**  
Pursuant to Section 1798.83 of the California Civil Code, if you are a resident of the State of California and Globalscape has an established business relationship with you, then you have the right to request the following at any time:  (a) information from Globalscape free of charge regarding the manner in which Globalscape shares certain personal information collected through the website with third parties who use such information for direct marketing purposes; and (b) the discontinuation (or opt-out) of Globalscape’s sharing of such information with such third parties.  Please submit any such request (“California Privacy Rights Request”) to privacy@globalscape.com with a subject line of “Your California Privacy Rights.”

For each California Privacy Rights Request, please state “Your California Privacy Rights” in the email or letter subject line, and clearly state the following in the body:  
a.    the nature of your request;  
b.    that the request is related to “Your California Privacy Rights;”  
c.    your name, street address, city, state, zip code and email address; and  
d.    whether you prefer to receive a response to your request by mail or email.

Globalscape is not responsible for a California Privacy Rights Request that is incomplete, incorrectly labeled or incorrectly sent.  You are solely responsible for the accuracy and content of your personal information, and for keeping your personal information current and correct.

**16\. International Users**

**•    Data Controller**  
Globalscape, Inc. is the data controller of the personal information you provide on our websites.  You may contact Globalscape, Inc. at privacy@globalscape.com.

**•    Purposes of processing and legal basis for processing**  
As explained above, we process personal data in various ways depending upon your use of our websites.  We process personal data on the following bases: (1) with your consent; (2) as necessary to perform a contract when you request services; and (3) as necessary for our legitimate interests in enhancing our web services and providing you with marketing materials.  

**•    Right to lodge a complaint**  
If you are a user in a European Union member state or in a European Economic Area country, you have the right to lodge a complaint about our data collection and processing actions with the supervisory authority concerned.

**•     Right to Erasure**  
If you are a user in a European Union member state or in a European Economic Area country, you have the right to request that personal data about you be deleted or erased.  If deletion of your data should not be possible for technical or legal reasons, we will block the respective data instead.

To request deletion or blocking of personal data, or revoke previously granted consent, please contact us at privacy@globalscape.com.

**•     Right to Revoke Consent for Processing of Personal Data.**  
If you are a user in a European Union member state or in a European Economic Area country, and you consented to Globalscape’s processing of your personal data, you have the right to revoke the consent you previously provided.

To revoke previously granted consent, please contact us at privacy@globalscape.com.

**•    Right to Data Portability**  
If you are a user in a European Union member state or in a European Economic Area country, you have the right to request that the personal data you have provided to us, and that we process by automated means, be provided to you or another controller in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format.

**•    Transfers**  
We are headquartered in the United States of America. Personal data may be accessed by us or transferred to us in the United States. The European Commission has not determined that the United States ensures an adequate level of protection for personal data.  By providing us with personal data, you consent to this transfer. We will protect the privacy and security of personal information according to this Privacy Policy, regardless of where it is processed or stored.  By providing us with personal data,  you consent to the storage or processing of personal data in the United States and acknowledge that the personal data will be subject to the laws of the United States, including the ability of governments, courts or law enforcement or regulatory agencies of the United States to obtain disclosure of your personal information.

**17\. Mergers and acquisitions**  
Globalscape may decide to sell, buy, merge, or otherwise reorganize its business.  If that occurs,  you will be notified via email or a prominent notice on our website of any ownership change and any changes in the use of your personal data. These types of transactions may involve the disclosure of personal data to prospective or actual purchasers, or receiving it from sellers. We seek appropriate protection for personal data in these types of transactions.

**18\. Contact us**  
Should you have any further questions or suggestions regarding the protection of your personal data processed in connection with the use of our websites, please contact us at privacy@globalscape.com.

**19\. Changes to our privacy policy**  
We regularly review and revise our Privacy Policy.  We make changes to the Privacy Policy available on this page and note that the policy has been updated.  If we make material changes to how we treat your personal data, we will notify you by email to the primary email address specified in your account and through a notice on our home page.   

This Privacy Policy was last updated on the 25th of May 2018.
